Michael CLAUDE

- 06 89 18 79 85
- michael.claude.web@gmail.com
- 15 rue Rollin 75005 Paris

ABOUT

33 years old with 10 years of experience in different web professions but mainly in front web integration and development. Versatile, autonomous, I have good adaptability and good human contact. I put my skills and my multiple experiences to good use to best meet the needs and challenges that are exposed to

LANGUAGES

French
English
Spanish

SKILLS

Web integration

Html/CSS/SCSS,Boostrap 4, Responsive design, UI/UX Conception, Media Queries

Web front development

Javascript/Jquery/Ajax, Angular 1, Angular 2+, nodeJs, git, json, phonegap

CMS

Wordpress, woocommerce, Joomla

Web back development

PHP, SQL, creation of databases

Softwares

Visual studio code, Sublime Text 3, Photoshop, After Effects, Final cut, ableton live.

TRAINING

2009 CFA com (alternation) Multimedia scriptwriting license and Open Distance Training

2008 CFA com (alternation) BTS, TIM (Multimedia Integration Technician)

2006 CFA com (alternation) Year Upgrade Art

2005 lycée Uruguay France (Avon) Tray STT Action Commercial Communication

HOBBIES

Music: musician, drums, percussions, composition, MAO + bands websites

Social: volunteering in an association: distribution of food and clothing to homeless people + website

Environment: Help in an association of shared gardens + website

WEB FRONT INTEGRATOR DEVELOPER

PROFESSIONAL EXPERIENCE (10 years)

From 2010 to the present day | Front & back Web development, e-commerce, intégration, project management,UI/UX conception, customer support | Freelance (in parallel with my salary activities)

Digikoder (from 2010 to present day) for my customers as freelancer >> Design and management of various web / multimedia projects, graphic models, ergonomics, video editing, management of domain names, shared and dedicated OVH web hosts (webmin/ubuntu).

- >> Implementation of several websites with CMS **wordpress**/joomla and html5/css3/javascript/jquery/php/ajax, SEO, speed, security optimisations.
- >> Driving and conceptualizing personal projects, websites, web and mobile applications (phonegap).
- >> Creation of E-commerce sites with CMS, wordpress woocommerce
- > Greenpoint: (2019), NetResto, Nouslibertins.com: (2018)
 Integration of front and back office web interfaces html, css, sass, responsive design in a small team.
- > One color: (2015 2017)

Creation of websites in html, css, js ,ajax, php, wordpress, woocommerce for a renowned photographer Frédérique Mercier as well as for its customers including the migration of a large online clothing store (payment system, inventory management, import of products, price update). Seo optimisations

> Teaminside : (2015)

Integration / web development front responsive design for the new website of the MMA (assurance).

> Living Actor: (2014)

Integration of the new website from graphic models in html, css, javascript, responsive design.

2017-2018 | Front web developer / Project Manager | AB PRODUCTION (Angular5/js vanilla/jquery/HTML5/CSS3/git/ajax/grunt/bower/scss/Jira) - OEC

> graphic, technical, UI/UX overhaul of internal business tools with angular 5-6.

2017 | Front web developer / Project Manager | Publicis Conseil (js vanilla/jquery/HTML5/CSS3/git/ajax/grunt/bower/scss/gitlab/Jira) - OEC

- > Project manager of the ACCOR HOTEL website redesign.
- > Web front integrator developer on the ACCOR HOTEL project.

2016 | Front web developer | Louis Vuitton - Seloger.com (js vanilla/jquery/HTML5/CSS3/git/ajax/grunt/bower/scss) - OEC

> Ticketing / debugging, front end web integration development, optimizations.

2014 | Front web developer, Project Manager, UI/UX conception, integrator, project management | Digikoder (js/AngularJS

1/jquery/HTML5/CSS3/ajax/cordova/wordpress/woocommerce) - OEC

- > Creation of a wordpress site for the opening of a restaurant in Ibiza
- > Design and production of a local social network mobile application with web technologies (html, css, js, ajax, php, phonegap)

2014 | Front/Back web developer, Project manager | Res-novae (js vanilla/HTML5/CSS3/Air/PHP/ajax/joomla/SQL/Adobe AIR) - OEC

> Development and management of a desktop application for BEL company salespeople allowing them to consult a file and news bank with back office for update management.

2009-2013 | Front/Back web developer conceptor, Project Manager, webmaster, multimedia integrator, video editor, graphism | Mediaways (js vanilla/HTML5/CSS3/Air/PHP/ajax/joomla/SQL/Adobe AIR) - OEC

> Complete overhaul of the Rich Media web tool for text, image and video synchronization sold by the company + creation of a complex web platform for automated generation of the tool for each client.